Yesterday, out of nowhere, Amazon released its own AI IDE named Kiro, yet another VS Code
4 that will compete for the hearts and minds of programmers alongside editors like Kurser,
Windsor, Firebase Studio, and Copilot just to name a few.
It's powered by Claude Sonnet 4.0, but claims to be better at handling complexity than
these other sloppy tools thanks to an approach called Spectraven Development.
And right now it's free to use, but that's not the only good news for developers.
The Chinese just dropped Kimi K2, an open-weight agentic coding model that approaches the
performance of Claude.
These tools are so powerful, they might even be able to fix pirate software's code,
so the entire internet can finally stop dunking on this guy.
In today's video, we'll try out Amazon Kiro to find out if it truly is the Kurser Copilot
Killer.
It is July 16th, 2025, and you're watching the Code Report.
You might remember a few weeks ago when OpenAI was going to buy that other VS Code 4,
Windsor, $4 Billions of Dollars.
Well, that deal fell apart, then Google came in and gutted all the talent from the company
by convincing them to abandon ship and join Google for $2.4 Billion.
That screwed over many of the employees at Windsorff, but it's not a total loss because
then cognition, the creator of Devon, is swooped in after Google to buy up all the scraps.
And what appears to be an all-stock deal.
We live in a world where people will literally pay you billions of dollars for a VS Code
4 because all these companies are desperate to get developers to use their products.
But the company taking the lion's share of developer money is Anthropic.
Primarily thanks to its Cloud Code CLI tool.
Anthropic went from less than a billion in revenue last year to now over 4 billion this
year.
And one of their biggest investors is Amazon, which has pumped $8 billion into the company
so far.
Now, if you don't use Cloud Code, there's a good chance you use an IDE-like cursor powered
by Cloud instead.
It's great, but the problem is that Anthropic has cursor by the balls.
If developers want to use Cloud, a cursor needs to act as a middleman and price it in a way
that can eventually become profitable.
Recently, cursor tried to make some tweaks to its pricing that caught some customers off
guard because suddenly their vibe coding bill became way higher.
And cursor had to later come out and apologize publicly.
If that weren't bad enough, now here comes Kuro.
It's also a VS Code 4 with many similar features.
And based on its initial pricing, it looks like you'll be able to get much more out of
Cloud for a much lower price.
I'm sure it's a total coincidence that Amazon chose to release Kuro right now, but let's
try it out and find out if it's any good.
Overall, I think the UI looks really nice, but it did feel a bit slow and was missing
small features like chat checkpoints and cursor.
I also ran into a bunch of delays because the service was overloaded.
But these are issues you would expect on an early release product like this.
The biggest difference, though, is that Kuro tries to prevent you from generating a bunch
of slop all at once.
Rather than go straight to code, it encourages you to start in this requirements and defile
which defines things like the user story and acceptance conditions.
Then once that plan is in place, it can move on to the design, which is the design document
that outlines implementation details like your component structure, your testing strategy,
error handling strategy, and so on.
And then finally, those two documents get combined together to create an implementation
plan.
Each task will outline the code the AI should write, and you can click this button in the
IDE to start it.
Overall, the process felt a bit slower, but it does feel like a much more sane approach
if you're building something serious or working with a team of multiple people.
Overall, it feels like an IDE designed to appeal to developers working in enterprise
where things like design documents and consistent code quality matters.
Currently, Kuro is close source and only powered by Claude, but in the future,
they plan to offer other models.
Right now, Amazon is offering it for free, so using it to no brainer,
but only time will tell if it becomes a legit cursor killer.
But if you want to harness the full power of AI, you need to understand the math
and computer science behind it.
And you can do that today for free with Brilliant, the sponsor of today's video.
There how AI workscores teaches you how to build a functioning language model from scratch,
and lets you experiment with things like feature vectors to edit facial expressions and images.
So this hands-on approach to learning helps you master challenging concepts over time,
and is proven to be six times more effective than watching video lectures.
Try everything Brilliant has to offer for free for 30 days by visiting brilliant.org slash
virus ship. Or scan the QR code on screen to get 20% off an annual premium subscription.
This has been the code report, thanks for watching, and I will see you in the next one.